-애로우 지난 시즌에서-
Last season on
"Arrow"...
이 도시는 여전히
구원이 필요해
This city still
needs saving.
-후드에 의해서 아니라
-도시엔 영웅이 필요해
Not by the Hood.
It needs a hero.
시련을 견뎌내면
더 강해지기 마련이지
If you survive a crucible,
you grow the stronger for it.
이게 그걸 일깨워줄거야
This is to remind you of that.
팀에 합류한걸 환영한다
Welcome aboard.
사라는 암살단에
충성을 맹세했어
Nyssa: Sara swore
her allegiance
to the league
of assassins.
- 돌아가는 거야?
- 사라는 잘 지낼거야
You agreed to go back?
Laurel: She'll be OK.
그래, 물론
잘 지내겠지
Yeah,
I know she'll be OK,
하지만 그게
문제가 아니야
but OK what is what
bothers me. [Grunts]
아빠?
괜찮아요?
Dad? Dad!
슬레이드의 계획은
내게 모든걸 빼앗는 거였어
Slade's whole plan was to take
everything from me. He did.
그리고 성공했지
슬레이드가 로렐을 납치한건
내가 그녀를 사랑한다 생각해서지
Slade took Laurel because
he wants to kill the woman I love.
- 그래서요?
- 그는 잘못된 여잘 골랐어
So?
So he took the wrong woman.
내가 사랑하는건 너야
알겠어?
I love you.
Do you understand?
[Both grunting]
지난 5년 동안
섬에만 있었던 건 아니야
The five years that I was gone,
I wasn't always on the island.
저는 아만다 월러에요
My name is Amanda
Waller, Mr. Queen.
홍콩에 오신걸
환영합니다
Welcome
to Hong Kong.
[Oliver grunting
and gasping]
52번가에서 표적발견
동쪽으로 가고있다
Oliver: Got him.
Coming up 52nd street, heading east.
알았다, 아니면
로저라고 해야하나요?
Copy that. Or is it Roger?
I never know the difference.
항상 그 차이를
잘 모르겠어요
John, there's an illegal
shipment of RPGs headed your way.
존, 그쪽으로 불법 무기를
잔뜩 실은 차량이 가고있어요
로저. 가고 있다
Roger. I'm on it.
아, 그럼
로저라고 하는게 맞군요
Oh, so it is Roger.
무기를 확보했다
RPGs are secure.
I've got eyes on.
Roy!
로이!
그쪽으로 갈게
We're coming to you.
[Tires squealing]
[Thunder]
빈센트 스틸그레이브
Vincent Steelgrave...
넌 도시를 망쳤다
You have failed this city.
애로우 시즌3 1화
기미갤 12:51 제작
??Arrow 3x01 ??/font>
The Calm
Original Air Date on October 7, 2014
그동안 수고하신 무수한 기미갤의
자막제작자 분들께 이 자막을 바칩니다
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
@elder_man
상업적 이용 금지, 배포 자유, 수정금지
[Sirens in distance]
애로우가 방금 또다른
지명수배자를 잡아들이며
The Arrow just
took down another
한 건 해냈는데요
one of the city's
most wanted,
그 덕에 지난 5개월동안
시 범죄율이 급락한 건
and there's no denying that
the city's crime rate
매우 자명한 사실입니다
has plummeted
in the past five months.
천만에요
You're welcome.
하지만 실업율과
그 인구 또한 그렇죠
But so has its unemployment
rate and its population.
우리는 지난 몇년동안
두번의 테러 공격을 겪었습니다
We have experienced
two terrorist attacks in as many years.
스탈링 시는 죽어가고 있어요
감옥에는 범죄자들이...
Starling City is dying,
and a prison full of criminals--
채널 좀 돌려봐
Take another
off the board.
이런 모양새라면
조만간 스탈링 시에
We keep this up, there will only be
two types of criminals
두 범주의 범죄자만 남을껄
left in Starling City--
the ones we put away
-우리가 감옥에 넣은 이들과...
-언제 잡힐까 겁먹는 이들이지
and the ones that
are running scared.
저건 뭐야?
What's that?
고사리에요
빛만 있으면 잘 자란다고 해서요
A fern.
It thrives on the light.
당신이 이제 여기서 사니깐
I thought since you were
living here now,
그럴듯한 화분도 좀
있어야 하지 않겠어요?
the place could do
with a little sprucing.
침대 사줘도 되는데
I let you buy me a bed.
You were sleeping
on the floor.
원래 바닥에서 주무시잖아요
[Phone vibrates]
Another text
from Thea.
테아한테 문자왔어요
Where is she now?
지금은 어디래요?
아말피 해안
Amalfi coast.
사진 보내라고 해놨어
I keep telling her
to send photos.
저 잠깐 산책
좀 갔다올게요
I'm going to go
do a patrol, clear my head.
로이
Hey.
오늘 정말 잘해줬어
You did really
good tonight.
저도 가볼게요
I'm going
to head out, too.
내일 아침 일찍
근무 교대가 있어요
I have to pull an early shift
at work today,
제가 한 말중에 가장
암담할지 아닐지는 모르겠지만요
which may or may not be the most
depressing thing I've ever said.
그래도 우리
내일 저녁에 보는거지?
But we're still on
for tomorrow night?
물론이죠,
당신이 완벽한 CEO가 되도록
Absolutely.
I am going to turn you
탈바꿈 시켜 줘야죠
into corporate
master of the universe.
이사회가 당신한테
Those board members
are going to be begging
퀸 회사를 다시 못팔아서
안달날 걸요
to sell Queen Consolidated
back to you and your backers.
나도 좀 나가볼게
I'm going
to roll out, too.
라일라가 아기침대를
못 만들어서 안달이야
Lyla has me trying to build
the bassinet from hell.
꼭 나같네
That reminds me...
I figured since you and Lyla
are having a girl...
여자아이니깐...
Man, you cannot
afford this.
근데 너 이런거
살 돈 없지 않아?
응, 그래서
내가 직접 만들었어
I can't afford anything,
which is why I made it.
그나마 내가 할 줄 아는게
화살촉 만드는 거잖아
Arrowheads, one of the few things
that I can make.
정말 예쁘다
고마워
Well, it's beautiful.
Thank you.
축하한다, 임마
Congratulations, John.
아기 뿐만 아니라
And not just on the baby.
너랑 라일라가 행복해서
다행이야
You and Lyla are happy.
있잖아, 너도 좀
네 생활을 가져봐
Well, you know,
you should try it some time.
내 전 여자친구는
암살단 멤버였고
Last girlfriend, she's in
the League of Assassins.
그 전 여자친구는
전-전 여자친구를 쏴 죽이려했지
My girlfriend before that,
she shot my girlfriend before that.
I'm not...not exactly
a catch at the moment.
아직 난...
그럴 상황이 아니야
펠리시티라면
괜찮을지도 몰라
Maybe Felicity will
change all that.
It's...It's not the right time.
아직은... 때가 아냐
지금만큼 좋은 상황은
없을거야
Things are as good now
as ever will be, Oliver.
너도 펠리시티를
사랑하잖아
And you love her.
직접 그렇다고 말했고
You even told her so.
그건 슬레이드를
속이려고 그랬던 거잖아
I was trying to fool Slade.
알아
Yes.
Except now the only
person you're fooling is yourself.
지금은 네가 네 자신을
속이고 있단 것만 빼면
아무튼 고마워
Thanks again.
[Horns honking]
[Dialing]
[Gunshot]
[Crowd screaming]
[All screaming]
[Both grunting]
[Speaking Chinese]
말했잖아
나 중국어 못한다니깐!
I told you,
I don't speak Chinese!
나도 말했잖아
And I told you,
you try to escape again,
또 도망치려 하면
죽을때까지 패주겠다고
I beat you senseless.
[Sirens in distance]
Steelgrave took
a plea for 15 to 20.
스틸그레이브가 20년형을
15년형으로 줄여달라고 탄원냈어
그쪽 변호사한테 애로우가
수집한 증거를 갖다주니
His lawyer folded
like a deck chair
after I hit him with
the evidence that the Arrow gathered.
아주 깨갱거리던 걸
잘했어
Good work.
네가 범죄자를 잡으면
내가 그들을 요리하는 거지
You catch 'em,
I cook 'em.
너무 크게 말했나?
Did I say that
too loud?
아냐, 괜찮아
No, you're fine.
우리가 이렇게 비지니스 파트너가
될 줄 누가 알았겠어
Did you ever think that we'd
end up as business partners?
이것땜에 날 부른거야?
Is that why you invited me
down here, Laurel?
스틸그레이브 뉴스 알려주려고?
To see Mr. Steelgrave
sent off into his new life?
아니
No.
깜짝 선물이 있어
I have a surprise
for you.
너네 아버진
여기서 뭐하시는 거야?
What's your dad doing here?
봐봐
You'll see.
잠깐만
I'll be right back.
Mm-hmm.
-아빠
-응, 왔니
Dad.
Hey.
좀 어때요?
Hi. How are you?
내 승진 기자회견에
Uh, well, if they had told me press
conferences came with a promotion,
나도 한마디 좀
하고 싶다고 했지
I would tell them I prefer
getting shot at.
Good thing your doctors
주치의가 선택의 여지를
안 줘서 다행이네요
didn't give you
a choice, then.
얘야, 내가 현장에서
더이상 못 뛰는게
You know, you could
try to hide the fact
그렇게 기쁘다는 듯이
말하면 무척 섭하단다
that you're glad I can't
get out in the field anymore.
아빠가 안전해서
그저 기쁠 따름이에요
I can't hide that I'm glad
that you're safe.
What's all this?
그래서
이 행사는 뭐야?
깜짝 선물이라니깐
Your surprise.
[Microphone feedback]
모두들 와주셔서
감사합니다
Lance: Uh, thank you all--ahem,
excuse me, thank you for coming.
Five months ago,
this city was under siege.
5개월 전, 도시는
공격을 받았습니다
경찰은 후드 쓴 사내를
업신여겼었죠
And the SCPD rallied
behind a man in a hood.
제가 이렇게
서장이 되었는데도
Well, I ended up
with a captain's rank,
그에게 변변찮은
인사 한 번 못했네요
and he didn't even
get a thank you.
오늘에서야 그에게
감사 인사를 전하고 싶습니다
But today, he does.
'Cause today,
the Starling City police department
오늘부러 공식적으로
스탈링 시 경찰서는
is formally recognizing
the individual
애로우라 불리는
이 개인에게
known as the Arrow.
And I'm using
my new position
제 새로운 권한으로
그를 잡으려는
모든 반-자경단 임무를
to disband
the anti-vigilante task force
해체할 것을
명령하는 바입니다
charged
with capturing him.
고마워
Thank you.
자경주의를 허락한다는
말이 아닙니다
Now make no mistake--
vigilantism will never be tolerated.
이 도시의 이름으로,
그것을 수호한 자를
But I refuse to hunt,
in the name of this city,
더이상 쫓지 않겠다는
뜻일 뿐입니다
the hero who saved it.
저런 쓰레기는 꺼버려
Shut that crap off.
Less heat on the Arrow
애로우를 안잡는다면
우리를 잡는다는 소리잖아
means more heat on us.
그리고 화기단속국은 우리
유탄발사기를 압수했고 말이지
And the ATF now has our shipment
of grenade launchers.
우리 물건을 가져갔다고?
They got our
shipment already?
도대체 뇌물은 왜 먹인거야?
What are we paying
bribes to the cops for?
We have a more
pressing concern.
우리한테 관심이
더 집중될거야
리더십 부족 좀 보게
Lack of leadership.
나를 지명할게
반대 의견 있나?
I nominate myself.
Any objections?
어, 좀 많은데
Yeah, a few.
말해봐
Oh, illuminate me.
뭐부터 시작할까?
네 이상한 말투는 그렇다쳐도
Where do I start?
It's not just that you talk funny.
넌 사업에 관해선
하나도 모르잖아
You don't know
the first thing about business.
그저 길거리
마약상인 주제에
You're just a low level
street dealer, a pill pusher.
그냥 마약이 아니야
Oh, those pills I push?
'버티고'라는 이름이 있다고
Are known as Vertigo.
In the wake
of the count,
카운트에 뒤이어
그의 조합공식을
조금 손봤지
I tinkered some
with his formula,
특정 버섯을 섞었거든
(*일부 버섯에는 환각기능이 있음)
introduced an additive produced
by certain mushrooms.
내가 만든 버티고는
My Vertigo
reveals the face
네 가장 큰
두려움을 보여주지
of your greatest fear.
[Growls]
뭘 말하고 있었더라...
As I was saying...
리더십 부족에
저를 추천하는 바입니다
Lack of leadership.
I nominate myself.
반대 의견 있나요?
Any objections?
옳은 결정을 하신겁니다
Our course of action
is straight as an arrow.
여러분
Gentlemen...
우린 그를 죽일거에요
We're going
to kill him.
펠리시티
업무는 좀 어땠어?
Hey, hey!
How was work?
그건 업무가 아니에요
"It" is not work. It is a soul crushing
exercise in misery
건강을 파는
영혼을 부시는 행위죠
that offers health and dental.
Suffice it to say,
지금 전 이사회가 당신 회사를
되팔도록 굉장히 돕고 싶어요
I am highly motivated to help convince
the board to sell you back the company.
안타깝게도, 당신은 회사를
운영할 자질이 부족하지만요
Unfortunately, you don't really have the
qualifications to run Queen Consolidated,
하지만 당신은
열정이 있어요
but what you do have
is passion.
회사에 신경쓰고, 그곳에서
일하는 사람들을 염려하죠
You care about the company
and the people that work there.
That's what you have
to get across to them.
그걸 어필해야 해요
You got to speak
from the heart.
가슴에서 우러나는 말을 하세요
Felicity...
펠리시티...
나랑 저녁 같이 안먹을래?
Would you like to go out to
dinner with me?
-저 진지해요, 올리버
-나도 그래
I'm being serious here, Oliver.
So am I.
제가 잘 이해한 건지
몰라서 그러는데...
I don't want to read...
Too much into this,
혹시 저한테
데이트 신청 하시는 거에요?
but are you yoking me
out on a date?
진짜 데이트 말예요?
데이트스러운 데이트 처럼요?
Like an actual date?
Like a...Date-date?
어... 저녁 같이 먹자는 의미가
데이트 신청 아닌가...
Su--I mean, the implication
being with dinner
보통 제가
더듬거리는 사람인데
that you...
Usually I'm the one
talking in sentence fragments.
[Chuckles]
Would you like to go
to dinner with me?
그래서 나랑
저녁 같이 먹을거야?
물론이죠
Yes.
가
Oliver: Go.
켈빈 니코가 방금
술집을 털었어
Kelvin Nico just knocked
over a liquor store.
니코는 스틸그레이브의 동료야
Nico's in Steelgrave's crew.
로이한테 사진좀 보내줘
Send his photo to Roy.
-펠리시티 연결해줘
-알겠어
Get me Felicity.
You got it.
지금은 좀 곤란한데요
Felicity: I can't
talk right now.
일하는 중이거든요
I'm at work.
고객님, 잠시만요
Could I ask you guys
just to wait one moment?
기술지원이 필요하단
연락이 들어와서요
Someone's calling
for tech support.
이러다 저 짤리면 어떡하죠
Oh, you are going to get me
so incredibly fired.
시 데이터베이스로 침입했어요
Okay, I am hacked into
the city's database. I am running
-당장 안면인식 돌릴게요
-이탈리안 음식 좋아해?
facial recognition...N...
Oliver: Do you like Italian?
-뭐라고요?
-오늘밤 말이야
What?
For tonight.
이탈리안 좋아하지?
싫어하는 사람이 어딨어
You like Italian, right?
Everyone likes Italian.
올리버, 당신 지금
고속 추격전을 벌이고 있어요
Oliver, you're in the middle
of a high speed chase.
멀티 태스킹하는 중이야
I'm multitasking.
찾았어요
하수구에 있네요
I got him.
He's in the sewer.
그의 전화를 추적할게요
그랜드&에임즈 상점 쪽에 있어요
I'm picking up his cell phone
underneath. He's at the corner
of Grand and Ames.
그리고 물론,
이탈리안 음식 좋아해요
And yes, I love Italian.
랜스 형사님, 아니, 서장님도
같은 방향으로 가고 있네요
Detective Lance-- captain Lance--
is also in pursuit.
천만에요,
전 가봐야겠어요
You are welcome.
I have to go.
형사, 고맙군
The Arrow:
Detective...Thank you.
-네가 다 처리했잖아
-오늘 한 말에 대해
You had it handled.
For what you said today.
그 이상을 해주면
더 좋을텐데
I wish I could do more.
그걸로도 충분해
You've already done
more than enough. I've got to go.
가야겠다
약속이 있거든
Some place
I have to be.
데이트라도 있나보지?
You got a hot date
or something?
(찡긋)
그래서 오늘 아침까지
Amanda: So this morning
makes how many
지난 5개월동안 얼마나
도망치려한줄 아세요?
escape attempts
in the last five months?
9번
Nine.
정말 이해를 못하시나 보네요
What we have here is a failure
to reach an understanding.
지옥에나 가버려
[Exhales]
Go to hell.
리안 유 화물선 안에서
So this is my reward
from saving you from drowning
익사직전인 당신을 구해준
대가가 이건가요?
in that freighter
off the coast of Lian Yu?
그래
Yeah.
왜 구해준 거야?
Why'd you do that?
궁금하시겠죠
That's need
to know.
간단히 말하면,
당신같은 사람이 필요했달까요
Suffice it to say, I have need
of a man of your capacity.
상관 없어
I don't care.
아무것도 상관없어
난 그저 집에 가고싶어
I don't care about anything
except going home.
명심하라고
And you should know that.
You should know
that I will never stop
난 절대로 도망치는걸
멈추지 않을테니깐
trying to escape.
그럼 당신도 명심하세요
And you should know that it's
extremely easy to kill someone
다들 이미 죽은 줄 아는 사람을
죽이는건 굉장히 쉽거든요
the world already
thinks is dead.
그럼 날 죽여
Kill me, then.
상관 없으니깐
I don't care.
다른 방법을 찾아야겠군요
We're going to have to try this
another way, then.
안녕하세요
기다려주셔서 감사합니다
Hi. Thank you for waiting.
괜찮아요
이것 좀 사고 싶어서요
Ah, no problem.
I just want to buy this.
이건 위성주파수 통신기
TX40인데요
This is a satellite frequency
communicator TX40.
네, 토르방화벽좀 뚫고 싶은데
Yeah, I'm trying to breach
a torsecured firewall
그러려면 헥사곤 위성에
침입해야해서요
and I need
something to help me
piggyback off
a keyhole hexagon satellite, so...
저도 해봤어요
I did that once.
공용 와이파이 신호를 해킹했었죠
Hacked a public
WI-Fi signal,
크라우드 소스
프로세싱을 통해서요
piggybacked using
crowd-sourced stealth processing.
Huh.
당신이 펠리시티 스모크군요
You're Felicity Smoak.
퀸 합병사에서 일하신...
Formerly of Queen
Consolidated.
왜 여기서 일하는 건지
여쭤봐도 될까요?
Do you mind if I ask you something--
why are you here?
제가 누군지
어떻게 아신거죠?
How do you know who I am?
당신같은 전문가에
관심있는 사람을 알거든요
I know a guy
who might be interested
in hiring someone
with your expertise.
죄송한데, 제가 지금 새로운 일을
구하고 있는게 아니어서요
I'm not actually...looking
for a new job right now.
신이 저를 도왔죠
God help me.
하지만 제가
이걸 도와드릴 수는 있어요
But I can help you buy this.
엄밀히 말하면
그러면 안되지만요
Unless I can't.
I mean, I shouldn't.
이걸 사시면 안돼요
You shouldn't buy this.
음, 장사를 어떻게 하는건지
이해가 잘 안가네요
OK. Clearly
you don't understand
how this whole
sales thing works.
신제품 TX50이
몇달 내로 나오거든요
The next gen model, the TX50,
comes out in a few months.
작년에 그걸 직접 만져봤죠
정말 대단하더라고요
I got to touch one last year.
Pure bliss.
토르레벨 방화벽을 뚫고싶으면
And if you want to breach
Tor-level security,
원격접속도구만 심으면 돼요
you should really
deploy a remote administration tool.
여기 좋은 제품이 있거든요
URL 주소에요
I have a good one.
Here's the URL.
고마워요
Thanks.
즐거운 해킹하세요
Happy hacking.
그러길 바래요
I certainly hope so.
False alarm.
가진통이었어요
확실해요?
이런 수축은...
Are you sure?
These contractions...
아직 4센치도
이완이 안되셨는걸요
Just Braxton-Hicks. You're not
even four centimeters dilated.
M1A1 같은 느낌이에요
I feel like an M1-A1.
엄청나게 큰 탱크
말하는 거에요
It's a tank.
Think a big, big tank.
그래도 병원에
오셔서 다행이에요
You did the right
thing coming in.
당신의 남편분이...
You don't want
your husband--
-남자친구에요
-전남편이에요
boyfriend.
Ex-husband.
고속도로를 가로질러
아기를 데려오길 바라진 않잖아요
To be delivering the baby on the side
of the freeway.
이제 옷입으셔도 좋습니다
You can
get dressed now.
알겠습니다
All right.
[Exhales]
자기 괜찮아?
Are you OK?
물론이지, 임신 9개월째인건
내가 아니라 당신이잖아
Yeah, yeah, I'm not
the one that's nine months pregnant.
당신 좀 겁난 것처럼 보여
You look a little scared.
자기야, 난 탈리반과의
전쟁에서 승리하고
Honey, please, I've thrown down
with the Taliban,
Malcolm Merlyn,
and a host
말콤멀린, 미라쿠루를 맞은
인간병기와도 싸워봤다고
of Mirakuru-powered
human weapons.
당근 무섭지
I'm terrified.
[Both laugh]
퀸, 2명 예약했는데요
Queen, party of two.
-안녕
Hi.
Hi. [Chuckles]
[Chuckles]
-뭐라고요?
-아냐
What?
Nothing.
-난 그저...
-긴장된다고요?
I'm just--
Nervous?
맞아
Yeah.
문장이 둥둥 떠다니죠
Line forms behind me.
스카치, 얼음 없이요
Scotch. Neat.
저는 물 한잔이면 돼요
Just the water
for me, thanks.
정말 괜찮겠어?
Are you--are you sure?
술이 있으면 더 도움이...
The booze might sort of
help with the whole--
항불안제 3알을 이미 먹어서
술 마시면 안되거든요
the alcohol is not going to mix well with
the three benzos I took.
나 왜 이러지?
Am I being crazy?
도대체 뭐땜에 이렇게
긴장하는거지?
I mean, what do we have
to be nervous about?
글쎄, 우리는 이미
남들이 첫데이트에서 했을만한
Well, we've already
exhausted every topic
대화를 진탕 나눴으니깐요
that one would normally talk about
on a first date
두번째 데이트도, 세번째도
매번 다른 데이트도요
and a second date
and a third date,
and every date,
actually,
게다가 전 이미
당신이 옷벗은 모습도 봤구요
and I've already
seen you shirtless.
많이 봤죠 *-_-*
Multiple times.
항상 옷벗고 계셨잖아요
Shirtless,
all the time.
-고마워요
Thank you.
당신이 아직
나에 대해 모르는게 있어
There are still a few things
that you don't know about me.
뭔데요?
Please. Name one.
5년전 내가 실종됐을 때...
The five years that
I was away...
리안 유에만 있었던건 아니었어
I wasn't always on Lian Yu.
짐작은 했죠
I thought so.
어디 있었는데요?
Where were you?
홍콩... 한번 갔지
Hong Kong...for one.
그리고 요즘
거기 있었던 일들이...
And I have been thinking
a lot recently about...
자꾸 생각이 나
My time there.
The choices
that I had to make.
어쩔 수 없이 내렸던 선택들이
안좋았던 기억 투성이로 들리네요
Those years sound like they were full
of a whole lot of suck.
미안
I'm sorry.
조금 거북해서 그래
I'm just a little
out of my element.
내가 그곳에 있었던 동안
The entire time
that I was gone,
난 절대로...
I could never...
그 누구도 완전히
믿지 못했어
completely trust someone.
And when that
goes on long,
너무나 오랬동안 그랬지
you stop...
사람을 한 사람으로 보기를
멈추게 된거야
seeing people for people.
네가 보는건
위협들이었어
You see...
threats.
타겟이거나
Or targets.
내가 집에 오기로 결정했을 때
And when I decided
to come home, I...
그런 내 모습을
어떻게 멈출지 몰랐어
I just didn't know
how to turn that part of me off.
그러다 네 사무실에
가게 되었고
Then I walked
into your office.
You were the first person
that I could see as a...
내가 처음으로
사람을 한 사람으로서
a person.
보게 된거야
네겐 뭔가 다른게 있었어
There was just
something about you.
알아요, 전 펜을
씹고 있었죠
Oh, yeah, I was
chewing on a pen.
빨간 펜이었어
It was red.
[Beeping]
GPS에 의하면
레스토랑에 있다네요
GPS shows him
in the restaurant.
애로우가 거깄는게 확실하다
The Arrow's
definitely in there.
그를 찾으려면
더 가까이 가야해
If we're going to find him,
we got to get in close.
충분히 가까워
We're close enough.
우리가 하는 일 때문에
Do you remember when I told you
that because of what we do,
내가 정말로
아끼는 사람과는
I didn't think that
I could be with someone
that I...
함께할 수 없다고
말했던 거...
That I could
really care about?
혹시 기억나?
네 기억해요
Yeah, I remember.
어쩌면 내가 틀렸나 봐
So maybe I was wrong.
[Whistles]
올리버, 당신...
Oliver, are you--
[grenade fires]
Ollie--
올리...
[explosion]
[Patrons screaming and crying]
펠리시티는 괜찮아요?
Is she OK?
잠깐 기절한 것 뿐이야
She's just knocked out.
모든 뉴스에서 보도중이야
경찰이랑 소방관이 현장에 도착했대
Saw it all over the news,
police and fire are on the scene.
그래, 거기 붙어있었으면
괜한 질문 공세나 받았겠지
Yeah, I didn't think
it was the best idea
to stick around
and answer questions.
네 말은 폭발이 거기서
일어난게 우연이 아니란거야?
You don't think you
and an explosion
at the same place
is a coincidence?
이것좀 봐요
Hey, check this out.
GPS에요
It's a GPS.
당신 자켓에서 발견했어요
지금은 파괴됐고요
I found it on your jacket.
It's wasted now.
스틸그레이브의 동료를
아까 잡았었잖아
You took out one
of Steelgraves' crew earlier tonight.
이걸 나한테 심으려고
팠던 함정이었군
It was a set up
so they could plant
that thing on me.
- 올리버, 무슨 생각하는 줄 알아
-아니, 그렇지 않아
Oliver, I know
what you're thinking.
난 다른 사람이 아니야
No, you don't.
Listen, I'm not other people.
네가 무슨 생각하는지 정확히 알아
그리고 네가 틀렸어
I know exactly what's going on
in your head, and you are wrong.
디글, 추적기를 심었는데
내가 그걸 못알아챘다고?
Diggle, somebody put a tracer on me
and I don't notice?
The only explanation...
유일한 설명은...
내가 흐트려졌단거야
I lost my focus.
[Dialing]
형사, 오늘 잡은 자와
공범이 오늘 폭발의 범인이야
The Arrow: Detective.
The person we took down earlier
is working with whoever's responsible
for tonight's explosion.
또다른 스틸그레이브의
조직원이겠군
Another one of Steelgrave's
crew, I'm guessing.
누가 지금 그 조직을
관리하는지 알아야겠어
Well, I need to know who's
at the top of that organization now.
어디서 그를 찾을 수 있는지도
And where I can find him.
알겠어
I'm on it.
[Gasps]
괜찮아, 괜찮아
여긴 안전해
Hey, hey, hey,
you're safe.
나 여깄어
넌 무사해
You're safe. I'm here.
[Footsteps]
워워워, 난 당신 편이라고
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa,
I'm on your side!
이것도 직접 처리할 셈인가
Got this handled, Detective.
건물을 폭파시킨 범인이야
These guys
blew up a building.
내가 그저 앉아만
있을 줄 알았어?
You think
I'm sitting this out?
용의자 이름은 버너 자이틀
Suspect's name
is Werner Zytle.
진짜 또라이야
He's a real head case.
머리 돌지 않게
조심해야겠네
Keep your head
on a swivel, then.
[Footsteps]
난 버너 자이틀이야
I'm Werner Zytle.
Ahh!
버티고라고 불러도 되고
You can call me Vertigo.
카운트는 죽었어!
The Count's dead!
어떤건 절대 죽지 않아
Some things never die.
You, for example.
당신도 그렇잖아
정말 좌절시킨다고
It's frustrating.
그말은 내가 더 열심히
해야한다는 거겠지
Just means I have to try
a little bit harder.
[Both grunting]
Ahh!
카운트는 죽었을지 몰라
사실이야
The Count might
be dead, true...
But his glorious
narcotic lives on--
하지만 그의
영광스러운 마약은...
with a few enhancements
더 향상된 모습으로
당신한테 최대의 공포를
보여줄거야
that will reveal to you
your greatest fear.
진실을 마주하는
것처럼 말이지
Like gazing
upon truth itself.
[Both grunting]
[Gunshot]
그한테 떨어져!
Get away from him
or get put down!
[Groans]
안 돼!
No...No!
[Beep]
펠리시티, 구급차 좀 불러줘
[Voice disguised]
Felicity, call an ambulance!
괜찮아요?
Are you OK?
워너가 당신한테 놓은건
꽤 강력한 향정신제에요
That was a pretty strong psychotropic
Werner hit you with.
랜스 형사 상태는 어떄?
[Clears throat] How's
detective Lance's condition?
안정됐어
스탈링 병원에 있어
Stable. He's at
starling general.
진단 기록을 해킹했어요
I hacked
the paramedic radio.
관상동맥 연축이 있었데요
He had a coronary
artery spasm
약 먹으면 치료 가능해요
괜찮을 거에요
treatable with medication.
He'll be fine.
너는 좀 어때?
How are you?
믿던지 말던지, 이것보다
더 심한 첫 데이트도 있었어요
Believe it or not,
I have had worse first dates.
거리를 수색해야겠어
Hit the streets.
워너의 활동은
아직 끝나지 않았어
Werner's agenda
can't stop with me.
-그의 계획이 뭔지 알아야해
-알겠어요
I need to know what he has planned.
On it.
나도 로이를 도울게
I'll back
him up.
로이가 한데잖아
넌 집에 가봐
Roy's got it.
Go home to Lyla.
올리버...
Oliver...
아까 일 땜에
그러는 거라면
If this is about
what happened, man,
위험은 내 직업의 일부야
risk is part
of the job.
디글 이건 그냥
정보원을 모으는거야
Diggle. It's just
Intel gathering.
로이도 충분히 할 수 있어
Roy can handle it.
I know we need to talk.
우리 얘기 좀 하자
우리의 데이트요, 아니면
그걸 망친거에 대해서요?
About our dinner or our dinner
getting blown up?
-둘 다
-알겠어요
Both.
It's OK.
우선 이자를 잡고나서 얘기하죠
We'll talk about it
after we catch this guy.
하지만 이사회는
다시 스케쥴을 잡아야겠어요
But maybe we should
reschedule the board meeting.
30분밖에 안남았잖아
It's in less
than an hour.
내가 할게
I've got this.
[Speaking Japanese]
[Groans]
사람들은 내가 중국어를
못한다는 걸 언제쯤 깨닫는거지?
When are people going to realize that
I don't speak Chinese?
일본어에요
Japanese.
You speak English?
영어를 말할 줄 아네?
그쪽이 중국어를
말하는 것보단 잘하죠
Better than
you speak Chinese.
여긴 어디죠?
Where am I?
우리 집이에요
Our home.
저와 제 남편의 집이에요
Mine and my
husband's.
Your husband?
남편?
우리 집에 온걸 환영해
Welcome to my home.
저녁 먹을래?
Dinner?
[Sighs]
[Monitor beeping]
의사가 나한테
소리지르면 안된다고 했어
I got to warn you, the doctors told me
not to get yelled at.
현장에 나가지 말란
의사의 충고를 무시할 정도로
Well, it's a good thing
you don't care about
your doctor's
instructions, then,
의사의 처방을 별로
신경쓰는것 같지 않던데요
since you're still
going out in the field.
사전건강 의료지시서가 뭔줄 아세요?
Do you know what an advanced
healthcare directive is?
환자가 죽을것 같을때
요구하는 종이에요, 아빠
It's what they ask for
when you're going to die, dad.
The night Sara left,
사라가 떠났을 때
the night
you collapsed,
아빠가 쓰러지신 날
응급처방 의사가 저한테
의료지시서를 요구했어요
the E.R. doctor asked me
if you had one.
[Sighs]
미안하다, 로렐
면목이 없구나
I'm sorry, Laurel,
I really am.
정말 미안하다
I'm sorry, sweetheart.
Then why do you keep
pushing yourself like this?
왜 자꾸 이렇게
자신을 힘들게 하는거에요
I don't know how.
어떻게 해야할지 모르겠다
너와 사라가 태어나기
전부터 난 경찰이었어
I've been a cop since before you
and your sister were born. It's all I know.
만약 내가 더이상
경찰이 아니라면
If I'm not a cop...
나는 뭐가 되는거지?
What am I?
당신은 제 아빠세요
You're my father.
그리고 전 아빠가 필요해요
And I need you.
네드 포스터와 얘기해봤는데
And I just spoke
to Ned foster.
이사회는 올리버한테
회사를 줄 의향이 있데요
He said the board is primed.
그냥 거기 나타나서
이사회를 열광시키면 돼요
You just have to go
in there and wow them.
당신은 잘 해낼거구요
Which I am pretty sure
is a business term.
죄송하지만 변수가 생겼어요
I'm afraid we have a situation.
또다른 입찰자가 나왔습니다
Apparently there's another
bidder for the company.
정말로요? 누군데요?
Really? Who?
레이 팔머입니다
Ray Palmer.
만나서 반갑습니다
멋진 회사군요
Nice to meet you.
Love your company.
또 만나서 반가워요, 스모크 양
Nice to see you again,
miss Smoak.
둘이 아는 사이세요?
You two know
each other?
늦어서 정말 죄송해요
교통이 장난이 아니더라고요
So sorry I am late.
Heh, traffic was terrible.
그래서 제 헬기를 타고왔죠
Which is why I took
my helicopter.
옥상에 주차해놨는데
괜찮겠죠?
I parked on your roof.
I hope that's OK.
헬기주차장이 아직은
유효한거 맞죠?
You guys validate, right?
젠장
Oh, frack.
Two years ago,
the people of Starling City
2년 전 스탈링 시의 시민들은
제가 죽은 줄 알았죠
thought I was dead.
저는 돌아왔습니다
I came back.
퀸 합병사도 그렇고요
And so can
Queen Consolidated.
스탈링 국립은행의
투자를 받는다면
With Starling National
Bank's new investment,
우리는 법정 재산관리에서 벗어나
미래로 향할 수 있습니다
we can take QC out of receivership
and into the future.
이 회사는 제 가족이에요
I mean,
this company's my family.
And as my mother
always said...
저희 어머니는
항상 말씀하셨죠
제게 가족보다 중요한건 없다고요
There is nothing more important
to me than family.
감사합니다
Thank you.
[Inhales,
exhales]
멋진 연설이네요
That was
a good speech.
앞지르기 힘들겠어요
Hard to top.
[Exhales]
오늘 와주셔서 감사합니다
Thank you all
for coming out today.
간단하게 하도록 하죠
I promise to be brief,
if not a little entertaining.
어, 그거 저희 스마트 워치인데
Ahh. Oh, that's one
of my new smart watches.
저도 그거 정말 좋아하거든요
I'm very proud of those.
어때요, 맘에 드세요?
You like it,
it works for you?
다행이네요.
그럼.. 과학은 숫자죠
Yeah, good. Anyway.
Science. Numbers.
These numbers show
QC's performance
이 숫자는 퀸씨가 관리했을 당시
회사의 실적입니다
under Mr. Queen's
management.
b-t-w라고 축약해서 부르겠습니다
I'm using that term
extremely, b-t-w.
또한 b-t-w, 이 숫자들은
월스트릿에서 가공하지 않은
Also b-t-w,
these numbers
aren't sanitized
for Wall Street.
순수한 숫자들입니다
This is raw
information
제가 직접 이 회사
서버에서 추출해냈죠
from your company's
own servers.
어떻게 우리 컴퓨터에 침투한거지?
How did he get into
our computers?
누군가 그에게 원격관리도구를
설치하라고 조언해줬거든요
Something tells me he deployed
a remote administration tool.
사실, 이 회사의 문제는
더 큰 문제에서 비롯된 거죠
But the truth is,
this company's woes are a symptom of
a much larger problem.
그 문제는 바로
스탈링 시입니다
And that problem
is Starling City.
회사가 위치한 이 도시가
죽어가고 있는데
Queen Consolidated
can't hope to survive
퀸 합병사가 생존하기란
불가능합니다
if the city
it's located in is dying.
Guess what? It is.
그럼 어떻게 할까요?
더이상 아무도 여기서
살고 싶어하지 않죠
Nobody wants
to live here anymore.
두 번이나
테러 공격이 있었는데
[Chuckles] And after
two terrorist attacks,
당연한거 아니겠어요?
who can blame them?
이 도시는 여전히
구원이 필요합니다
This city
still needs saving.
그게 이 회사에 대한
제 비젼입니다
And that is my vision
for this company.
재에서 일어어나는 것
뿐만 아니라
To not only see it
rise from the ashes,
이 도시를 새로운
지평선으로 이끄는 거죠
but to take this city with it
to that new horizon.
그리고 그 새로운 날에는
이름이 있습니다
And that new day has a name.
스타 시티
[Applause]
올리버
Oliver!
미안해요
I'm sorry.
저는 우리한테 유리하게
돌아갈 줄 알았는데
I really thought
it was going to go our way.
나도 그래, 하지만 팔머씨가
더 회사를 잘 이끌지도 몰라
So did I. But maybe the company's
better off with Dr. Palmer.
나는 작년에 실패했잖아
I couldn't make time
for QC last year,
이제서야 회사를 되찾으려 하다니
내가 어리석었지
and trying to get the company back now,
it's selfish.
예전의 내가 했을법한 일들이지
That's something
that the old me would have done.
지난 12시간은 내게
아무것도 일깨워주지 못했어
And if the past 12 hours
have reminded me of anything,
2년전, 나는
올리버 퀸을 포기하고
it's that two years ago, I made
the decision to put Oliver Queen aside
애로우가 되기로 결심했어
and be the Arrow.
It's not a choice I get to unmake.
그건 번복할 수
있는 결정이 아냐
어제 레스토랑에선
다르게 말했잖아요
Last night at the restaurant,
you didn't feel that way.
그동안 일어난 일을 봐
Look what happened,
Felicity.
올리버! 폭발사고는
당신 책임이 아니에요
Oliver! The explosion
wasn't your fault.
워너가 버티고를
내게 꽂으며 말했어
When Werner hit me
with the Vertigo dart,
그의 새로운 조합공식은
he told me
that his formula,
우리가 가장 두려워하는
보여준데
it shows us
our worst fear.
난 거기서
내 자신을 봤어
And I saw myself.
올리버 당신이 스스로를
두려워한다고 생각하는 건 아니죠?
You don't really think
you're afraid of yourself, do you?
내가 올리버 퀸으로 살게 되면
일어날 일들이 두려워
I think I'm scared
of what would happen
if I let myself
be Oliver Queen.
알아낸건 있어?
What did we find out?
우리가 시 범죄율을
얼마나 낮춰놓은지 알아?
You know how we've got
the number of crime bosses
in Starling City
down to three?
워너도 범죄율을
0퍼센트로 만드려 해
Well, this new guy, Werner,
he wants to make it zero.
결투를 받아들이지
Diggle: Take out
the competition.
미캐일 패트로브, 루시아노 코스타
신타와 시모사와
Mikhail Petrov, Luciano Costa,
Shintawa Shimosawa.
그들이 어딨는데?
What are their
locations?
아무 주소도 못 찾겠어요
I'm not getting anything
off of last known addresses.
워너가 지금 이들을
이동시키고 있을지 몰라
Werner could be
moving these guys right now.
저도 최대한 노력하고 있다고요
I'm going as fast as I can!
It's not like these guys
전 GPS를 심는 놈들처럼
민첩하지 못해서요
walk around with little GPSs
attached to them.
얘네도 GPS가 있다면 모를까
Unless they do.
페트로브, 코스타, 시모사와
Petrov, Costa, Shimosawa,
이들은 모두 가석방 상태거나
보석으로 풀려났어요
they're all on parole
or out on bail.
전자발찌
Ankle monitors.
근데 뭔가 이상해요
모두 같은 장소에 있네요
Can't be right.
They're all in the same location.
로켓 아레나에요
오늘 헤비급 싸움이 열려요
Rockets Arena.
The heavyweight title fight's tonight.
범죄자 두목한테는
크리스마스같겠죠
That's like Christmas
for crime bosses.
2만명 넘는
사람들이 모일거에요
There'll be like
20,000 people there.
한 명을 죽이려고
레스토랑을 날려버린 놈인데
He was willing to blow up a restaurant
to take down one man.
He'll blow up a stadium
to take down three.
세 명 잡겠다고 경기장을
날리는건 별거 아니겠지
Yeah, but an RPG won't do it.
I need you looking
그래, 하지만 RPG보단
더 큰 폭발물이 필요할거야
for a large explosive device.
로이, 준비해
Roy...suit up.
Where do you
want me?
나는 어디로 갈까?
여기
Here.
I can't have you
in the field anymore.
넌 더이상 현장에 오면 안 돼
Really?
What changed?
정말로?
뭐 때문에?
넌 곧 아빠가 되잖아
You're going to be a father.
[Chuckles] Oliver,
you've known for
올리버, 지난 5개월 동안도
난 아빠가 될 예정이었어
the past five months
I was going to be a father.
그래서 다시 물을게
So I ask you again--
-뭐 때문에 그래?
-나야
what changed?
I have.
My risks can't be your risks.
내 위험이 네게도
위험으로 남게 할 수는 없어
디글, 네겐 다른 삶이 있어
That...Diggle,
you have a life.
새로운 인생이지
You have a new life, it's...
내가 절대로 못 가질...
Life I can't have.
알겠어
I get it.
너랑 펠리시티가
폭발 사고를 겪고
You and Felicity
were in an explosion.
사람들이 죽었지
어쩌면 그게 너네였을수도 있어
People died, either one
of you could have.
하지만 살아남았잖아
But you didn't.
그게 널 뒤흔들게 하지 마
You can't let that
shake you, man.
랜스 형사는 지금
병원에 누워있어
Detective Lance is laying
in hospital bed right now
-내가 그를 현장에...
-잠깐, 이건 아니지
because I let him--
Wait, wait, wait!
랜스는 자기 스스로
결정을 내린거야
Lance is his own man who
makes his own decisions,
나 또한 그렇고
and so am I.
이번은 아니야
Not this one.
올리버, 난 지난 2년동안
네 십자군 전쟁에 동참해왔어
Oliver, I've given
the last two years
of my life
to your crusade.
거기서 내가 얻은게
뭔 줄 알아?
I don't know what
that's supposed to earn me,
스스로 결정을 내릴
최소한의 권리야
but it earns me at least the right
to make my own choices.
-아냐, 그렇지 않아
-이 병신아!!
No, it doesn't--
damn it, Oliver,
너 내가 아니면
열번도 넘게 죽었을거야!!!!
you would be dead
ten times over
if it wasn't for me!
네가 맞아
You're right.
하지만 이건
내 십자군 전쟁이지
But this is my crusade,
이게 내 결정인거고
which makes this my decision.
[Crowd cheering]
[Whistling]
Five minute timer.
5분 뒤에 터질거야
이봐, 뭘 기다려?
Come on!
What are you waiting for?
[Grunting and groaning]
내 파트너
My partner.
[Beep]
가
Go.
소이탄에 쓰이는
극파 주파수를 찾았어요
Felicity: I've isolated
a frequency spike
consistent with
an incendiary device.
경기장 아래
중앙터널에 있어요
It's in the maintenance tunnel
underneath the stands.
제가 폭탄을 처리하죠
I'll get the bomb.
그 개자식을 잡아오세요
Get the son
of a bitch.
더 맞고싶어서 왔나?
Back for more?
It's as if you've
developed an addiction
버티고에 벌써
중독된거 아닌가 몰라
to Vertigo.
[Distorted voices]
내 선택은 내가 한다
I've made my choice.
[Both grunting]
펠리시티
시간이 얼마 없어요
Felicity, we're running
out of time here.
알겠어, 네 설명대로라면
OK. From your description,
접이식 회로설계같은데
it sounds like
a collapsible circuit design.
펠리시티
Roy: Felicity...
노란 선을 잘라
Cut the yellow wire.
노란 선이 없어요
There is no
yellow wire.
알겠어,
다른 방법을 쓰자
OK, new plan.
천장을 보면
절연 파이프가 보일거야
Look above you, there should be
insulated piping
경기장 냉방시스템인데
프레온 가스가 있어
pumping the arena's AC system.
They're pumping freon.
그 파이프 하날 부셔서
폭탄에 조준해
You want to break one off,
aim it at the bomb.
폭탄을 아예 얼려버리는거야
You're going
to freeze the thing.
[Both grunting]
제대로 되는것
같지 않는데요
Roy: It's not working!
[Grunting]
설마 놀란거야?
Don't look so surprised.
내가 사라진지 얼마나 됐다고
I haven't been gone that long.
날 가둬봤자 별로
소용이 없을거야
Lock me down,
it doesn't matter.
버티고는 항상 존재하거든
There will always
be a Vertigo,
누군가 또 새로운
조합을 만들어내겠지
always someone to
pick up the mantle.
네가 그 힘을 준거야
You have given it
the power.
모르겠어?
Don't you see?
모르겠냐고
잘 지내는것 같네
난다 파르뱃은 어땠어?
You look well.
How's Nanda Parbat?
더웠지
Hot.
이렇게 얼굴보니 좋다
It's good
to see you.
다들 널 그리워해
You've been missed.
로렐 보러 가다가
너네 무전을 엿들었어
I was on my way
to see Laurel,
picked up
your radio chatter.
펠리시티한테 주파수좀
보완하라라고 해
You should tell Felicity mix up her
frequencies a bit.
조언 고마워, 그래서
돌아온건 영구적인거야?
That's a good tip.
And is this permanent, you being back?
그러면 좋겠는데
I hope so.
글쎄...
We'll see.
넌 어떻게 지내?
How are you doing?
난 뭐...
하는 일이 많지
I'm...working
through a few things.
조언 하나 해줄까?
Word of advice?
우리는 가면이 아니야
We're not our masks.
가면을 쓰고 있지 않을 땐
우리 삶에 사람이 필요해
And we need people in our
lives who don't wear one.
펠리시티!
Hey.
여기서 뭐하시는 거죠?
What are you
doing here?
저를 스토킹하고 있다는
답변 말고요
And the answer
better not be stalking me.
당신 핸드폰의 GPS를
추적하는게 스토킹이라면
Well, that depends
on whether you consider
pinging your phone's GPS
stalking. OK, guilty.
뭐, 스토킹이 맞네요
당신같은 전문가에
관심있는 사람이 있다고
But you know how I know a guy
who would be interested
저번에 말했던거 기억나요?
in hiring someone
with your expertise?
제가 그럴것 같거든요
Yeah, turns out
I could really use it.
누군가 제 핸드폰, 노트북
PC까지 다 해킹했어요
Seems somebody hacked
my cell phone and my laptop
and my desktop.
Gee, that's too bad.
이런, 정말 안됐네요
제 자료를 전부 *호저
방귀소리로 바꿔놨더라구요
(*고슴도치랑 비슷한 설치류)
All my data's been replaced by audio files
of porcupine flatulence.
그래서 그런 짓을
한 사람이 누구던 간에
And so I was hoping
that whoever did it
제가 저지른 잘못에
대해 사과하면
might be willing
to undo it
그걸 다시
복구해줬으면 해서요
if I apologized
for misleading them in any way.
그럼 되겠네요
That would probably work.
아, 그런데
Oh, unless, of course,
you did all that
그사람 친구 회사를 훔치려고
그런 짓을 한거였다면
to steal that person's
friend's company,
뾰족한 설치류의 방구소리에
익숙해지는 수밖에 없을것 같네요
in which case I would suggest
getting used to the sound
of spiky rodents farting.
전 아무것도 훔치지 않았어요!
I didn't steal anything!
아마 조금은 그랬을지도요
하지만 있잖아요
OK, maybe a little,
but as it turns out,
전 사실 그 데이터가
필요하지도 않았다고요!
I didn't even need the data.
I mean, you saw the speech.
제 연설 보셨잖아요
전 말로도 잘하거든요
It was a pretty good speech.
제 친구가
막 아기를 낳았거든요
My friends
just had a baby,
제 관심이 필요한 사람이
또 있어서 가봐야겠네요
so if you don't mind, there's another
slimy little human that needs my attention.
아, 그리고 있잖아요(b-t-w)
(*by the way의 약자. 팔머의 연설 비꼬는거)
Oh, and b-t-w,
저라면 당신 타블렛을
한번 확인해볼것 같아요
might want to check
your tablet while you're at it.
[Chuckles]
안녕하세요
Hey.
-왔어
-안녕
Hey.
Hi.
와, 정말 앙증맞네요
Oh, she is scrumptious!
축하해요 여러분
진심으로요
Mazel tov, guys, seriously.
고마워
Diggle: Thank you.
I can come back.
이따 다시 올게
아냐, 올리버
들어와
No, Oliver, come in.
정말 완벽한데
Oh, she's perfect.
축하해
Congratulations.
고마워, 올리버
Thank you, Oliver.
뭐가?
For what?
옳게 행동해줘서
For being right.
[Inhales, exhales]
내 딸을 보는 순간
The second I looked at her...
모든게 바뀌었어
Everything changed.
전 우주가...
The whole universe...
뒤바뀌었어
changed.
네가 맞았어
You were right.
여기서 나가려면
어떻게 해야하지?
How do I get
out of here?
당신은 못 나가
You can't leave.
그럼 한번
절 멈춰보시던가요
[Scoffs] Well, why don't you
try to stop me?
내가 그럴 수 있다는 거 알잖아
You've already learned I can.
계속해서
Repeatedly.
아만다 월러는 네가
그녀를 위해 일할 것을 원해
Amanda Waller wants you
working for her,
그녀는 뜻을 이룰거야
and she will have her way.
차라리 죽는게 낫겠어요
Yeah, well, too bad for her.
I'd rather die.
그 때문에 아만다는
다른 방법을 택했어
Which is why it's not
your life she's threatening.
네게 책임있는건 나야
I am to be responsible for you.
그녀가 당신을 자극할
좋은 방법을 찾았더라고
She's found the proper way
to motivate me.
아키오
Akio.
아만다는 우리 가족을
위협하고있어
She's threatened my family.
내가 널 보내주면
아만다는 가족을 죽일거야
She'll kill them
if I let you go.
우리 아버지가 좋아하던
속담이 하나 있지
My father had a proverb
he was once fond of.
사람은 두가지 이름으로는
살 수 없다
A man cannot live
by two names.
무슨 뜻인데요?
And what does that mean?
네 경우엔...
In your case...
선택의 여지가 없다는 뜻이야
I believe it means
not having any choice.
디글이 행복해보여서 다행이에요
Ahh. They look
really happy.
정말 예쁜 아기에요
She's beautiful.
그렇지
She is.
우리 얘기 좀 하자
We need to talk.
싫어요
I don't want
to talk.
알아요, 기대하지 못한
대답이었죠?
Which for me, I know, is a little
unprecedented.
하지만...
But...[Sighs]
우리가 얘기하면
우리사인 끝난거잖아요
As soon as we talk,
it's over.
미안해
I'm so sorry.
난 내가 애로우뿐만 아니라
I thought that I could be me
스스로의 다른 삶을
살 수 있을 줄 알았어
and the Arrow...
하지만 그럴 수 없어
But I can't.
아직은 아냐
Not now.
어쩌면 계속
그럴지도 모르겠어
Maybe not ever.
절대라고 말해봐요
Then say never.
희망고문 좀 그만해요
Stop...
Dangling maybes.
우리 사이는 절대
이뤄질수 없다고 말해봐요
Say it's never going to work out
between us.
당신이 저를 절대
사랑하지 않는다고...
Say you never
loved me, say you--
펠리시티
Felicity...
내가 널 사랑하지 않는다고
말하게 하지 마
Don't ask me
to say that I don't love you.
우리가 이에 대해 말하면
우리 사이는 끝이라고
I told you as soon
as we talked...
말했잖아요
It would be over.
[Cell phone vibrates]
Hello?
여보세요
저 배리에요
It's Barry.
배리 앨런
(*플래쉬의 주인공.
애로우 시즌2 9화 참조)
Barry Allen.
I woke up.
저 깨어났어요
(*플래쉬 1화랑 연결됨. 챙겨보삼)
I could use some advice.
조언이 필요해요
그리로 가지
I'll be right there.
이제 암살단에서 준
휴가 다쓴거 아니야?
And here I thought
that you used up
all of your League
of Assassin vacation days.
[Laughs]
You look great.
How's dad doing?
잘 지내는 것 같네
아빠는 어떠셔?
The same.
똑같지, 뭐
널 보면 좋아하실 거야
Seeing you will help.
I don't want him
to know I'm in town,
아직은 내가 여기에 온걸
알리고 싶지 않아
not just yet.
아빠한테 네가 여기 온걸
알리고 싶지 않다는 거야
You don't want him
to know you're in town,
아니면 그 이유를
말하고 싶지 않다는거야?
or you don't want him
to know why?
둘 다
Both.
This life, it...
나같은 삶은...
It's complicated.
좀 복잡해
우리를 위해 그런 선택을
할 필욘 없었어
We didn't want you
to choose it.
Not for us.
알아,
날 위해 그런거야
I know.
I chose it for me.
[Cell phone buzzes]
The Arrow--
애로우...
Oliver--
올리버가
busted someone who tried
to blow up Rockets Arena.
로켓 아레나를
폭발시키려고 한 자를 잡았어
검사님은 내가
그를 심문하길 원하고
And my boss wants me
to head to the station
to backstop the interrogation.
Laurel Lance.
로럴 렌스
항상 세계를 구하려 하지
Always trying
to save the world.
가족 내력인가봐
Runs in the family.
Love you.
사랑해
안녕, 사라
Man: Hello, Sara.
여기서 뭐하세요?
What are you
doing here?
안 돼!
Oh! No!
사라! 안 돼..
No! Sara!
사라!!!!!!
Sara!
안 돼, 안 돼....
No, no!
[Sobbing]
제발...
Please!
기미갤 12:51 제작
상업적 이용 금지, 배포자유, 수정금지
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
@elder_man